Ralph Ellison
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Papers of Ralph Ellison 1890-1996 (bulk 1933-1990)
MSS83111
Ellison, Ralph
46,100 items 231 plus 22 oversize 110 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
African-American author and educator. General correspondence, organizational correspondence and reports, family papers, drafts, notes, and production files for novels, essays, poetry, short stories, reviews, and other writings, speeches, lectures, and interviews, reference file, and miscellany documenting Ellison's career and development as a writer. Among the many works represented are Going to the Territory (1985), Invisible Man (1952), and Shadow and Act (1964).
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
Names:
Ellison, Ralph; Bellow, Saul--Correspondence; Brooks, Harry, 1895-1970--Correspondence; Calicutt, Harold--Correspondence; Cheever, John--Correspondence; Ciardi, John, 1916- --Correspondence; Clark, Kenneth Bancroft, 1914- --Correspondence; Davis, Henry B. O., 1911- --Correspondence; Dawson, William Levi, 1899- --Correspondence; Engle, Paul, 1908- --Correspondence; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967--Correspondence; Hyman, Stanley Edgar, 1919-1970--Correspondence; Jackson, Shirley, 1916-1965--Correspondence; Murray, Albert--Correspondence; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905- --Correspondence; Wright, Richard, 1908-1960--Correspondence; American Medical Center for Burma; Bennington College; Carnegie Commission on Educational Television; Colonial Williamsburg Foundation; Federal Writers' Project; Museum of the City of New York; Negro People's Theatre (Chicago, Ill.); New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.); Wake Forest University; Ellison, Fanny McConnell. Papers of Fanny McConnell Ellison; Ellison, Ralph. Going to the Territory; Ellison, Ralph. Invisible Man; Ellison, Ralph. Shadow and Act
Subjects:
African American authors; American literature--African American authors--Study and teaching
Occupations:
Authors; Educators
Administrative Information
Provenance:
The papers of Ralph Ellison (1914-1994), author and educator, were acquired by the Library of Congress from his widow, Fanny McConnell Ellison, through a gift, purchase, and deposit, 1995-1997.
Transfers:
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Audio and video recordings have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. Photographs have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Ralph Ellison Papers.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1914, Mar. 1 Born, Oklahoma City, Okla.
1933-1936 Attended Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala.
1938-1942 Researcher, Federal Writers' Project, Works Progress Administration Married Rose Poindexter (divorced 1945)
1939 Published short story "Slick Gonna Learn" in Direction
1940 Published short story "The Birthmark" in New Masses Published short story "Afternoon" in
American Writing, ed. Hans Otto Storm and others (Prairie City, Ill.: J.A. Decker)
1941 Published short story "Mister Toussan" in New Masses
1942 Managing editor, Negro Quarterly
1943-1945 Seaman, merchant marine
1944 Published short story "Flying Home" in
Cross Section, ed. Edwin Seaver (New York: L. B. Fischer)
Published short story "King of the Bingo Game" in Tomorrow
1945 Received Rosenwald Fellowship
1946 Married Fanny McConnell Buford
1948 Published short story "Battle Royal" in '48, The Magazine of the Year
1952 Published
Invisible Man (New York: Random House. 429 pp.)
1953 Received National Book Award for Invisible Man
1955-1957 Received American Academy of Arts and Letters Fellowship for study in Rome
1958-1961 Instructor, Bard College, Annandale-on-Hudson, N.Y.
1960 Published short story "And Hickman Arrives" in The Noble Savage
1961 Alexander White Visiting Professor, University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill.
1962-1964 Visiting Professor of Writing, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J.
1964 Published
Shadow and Act (New York: Random House. 317 pp.)
1964-1965 Visiting Fellow in American Studies, Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
1966-1972 Honorary consultant in American letters, Library of Congress
1967-1977 Trustee, John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, Washington, D.C.
1968-1979 Board of Directors, Educational Broadcasting Corp.
1969 Decorated chevalier Ordre des Arts et Lettres, France Awarded Presidential Medal of Freedom
1969-1982 Trustee, New School for Social Research, New York, N.Y.
1970-1975 Trustee, Bennington College, Bennington, Vt.
1970-1979 Albert Schweitzer Professor of Humanities, New York University, New York, N.Y.
1970-1985 Board of Directors, Museum of the City of New York, New York, N.Y.
1971-1984 Trustee, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
1972-1985 Board of Visitors, Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, N.C.
1975 Opening of Ralph Ellison Branch, Metropolitan Library System, Oklahoma City, Okla.
1985 Awarded National Medal of Arts
1986 Published
Going to the Territory (New York: Random House. 338 pp.)
1994, Apr. 16 Died, New York, N.Y.
1999 Posthumous publication,
Juneteenth (New York: Random House. 368 pp.)
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Ralph Ellison span the years 1890-1996 with the bulk of the items concentrated in the period 1933-1990. The collection documenting Ellison's career as author and educator includes nine series: Family Papers; General Correspondence; Organizations File; Writings File; Speeches, Lectures, and Interviews; Reference File; Miscellany; Closed; and Oversize.
The Family Papers contain personal material pertaining to Ellison, his wife, Fanny McConnell Ellison, and their parents, siblings, former spouses, and other relatives. A substantial file relating to Ellison's employment includes material from his many teaching appointments. Of particular interest are the notes and reports he compiled for the Federal Writers' Project of the Works Progress Administration (WPA). Fanny Ellison's employment papers document her work for the American Medical Center for Burma through the Harold L. Oram agency and her contribution as one of the founders of the Negro People's Theatre in Chicago. Also noteworthy are her drawings pertaining to the history of costume executed as a WPA project for the Chicago Board of Education. Household papers contain material on the Ellisons' property in New York, Key West, Florida, and Plainfield, Massachusetts. The latter includes insurance records of the fire which destroyed the first drafts of Ellison's unpublished Hickman novel. Other material in the family papers consists of biographical information, financial, legal, and medical records, school and military records, newspaper and magazine articles about Ellison, travel documents, notes, and printed matter.
The General Correspondence series contains Ralph and Fanny Ellison's incoming and outgoing letters to friends and business associates. Correspondents include institutions and businesses as well as individuals. Chief among them are Saul Bellow, John Cheever, John Ciardi, Kenneth B. Clark, William Dawson, Paul Engle, Langston Hughes, Stanley Edgar Hyman, Shirley Jackson, Albert Murray, Robert Penn Warren, and Richard Wright. Several of Ellison's letters to friends and acquaintances such as Harry Brooks, Harold Calicutt, and Henry B. O. Davis contain reminiscences of his childhood, college years, and early adulthood.
The Organizations File concerns a wide range of cultural, educational, and charitable institutions in which Ellison participated as an officer, advisor, or trustee. For example, he served on the governing boards of Bennington College, the Carnegie Commission on Educational Television, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, the Museum of the City of New York, the New School for Social Research, and Wake Forest University. Material in the file consists primarily of correspondence and reports.
The Writings File contains drafts, notes, and production material for Ellison's literary works. The material in an essays and essay collections file, arranged alphabetically by title, appeared as journal articles or chapters published in compilations by others. Material pertaining to Ellison's own collections, Shadow and Act and Going to the Territory, is also included in this section. Many of his essays were reworked and republished several times. Ellison also wrote poetry, reviews of books, films, and recordings, short stories, and forewords, introductions, and endorsements for literary works of others. There is evidence that Ellison wrote book reviews in the 1940s under the pseudonym David Wilson. An incomplete draft of his memoirs also contains notes and outlines. Dates in parentheses in the container list refer to the publication date; other dates refer to the creation and span of the material in the folder.
Material relating to Ellison's novels makes up the bulk of the Writings File. In order to show Ellison's approach to writing, his system of filing drafts alphabetically by title of episode rather than final story sequence has been maintained. Quotation marks are used to indicate episode titles devised by Ellison. A section relating to Invisible Man includes production material, publicity items, reviews, opera and film proposals, correspondence with publishers regarding various editions, foreign rights and translations, and the comments and criticism of others. A miscellany section in the Writings File contains bibliographies and literary criticisms of Ellison's works, plot ideas, notes, royalty statements, and information regarding copyrights, permissions, and reprints.
The Speeches, Lectures, and Interviews series demonstrates Ellison's popularity as a speaker at special events, club meetings, and university seminars. His customary subjects were literary, but also included music and art. During his fellowship at the American Academy in Rome, Ellison lectured at several European seminars. Ellison also held numerous teaching positions ranging from one semester as a visiting professor to appointments lasting for several years. Courses included the contemporary American novel and Russian literature. He was frequently interviewed for radio programs, magazines, and newspapers. Among his interviewers were Michael S. Harper, Irving Howe, and Robert Penn Warren. The three sections of this series, containing texts, correspondence, notes, and printed matter, are arranged chronologically.
The Reference File includes newspaper and magazine articles and other printed matter on subjects ranging from music, art, and literature to sports, politics, and civil rights. A large biographical section includes material on individuals whom Ellison either knew or considered interesting.
The Miscellany series contains address books, appointment calendars, invitations, programs, and ephemera. Also included are papers relating to the awards, citations, and honorary degrees awarded to Ellison. The Closed series consists primarily of correspondence, writings, and drawings which are too fragile for handling. Photocopies of each item have been placed where the original would have appeared in the collection. Material too large for the document boxes has been moved to the Oversize series.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in nine series:
Family Papers, 1890-1996, n.d.
General Correspondence, 1930-1996, n.d.
Organizations File, 1939-1994, n.d.
Writings File, 1935-1995, n.d.
Speeches, Lectures, and Interviews, 1945-1993, n.d.
Reference File, 1901-1995, n.d.
Miscellany, 1904-1994, n.d.
Closed, 1932-1994, n.d.
Oversize, 1923-1993, n.d.
Container List
- Family Papers, 1890-1996, n.d. (Box 1-34)
  Correspondence between family members, vital records, school papers, military records, household, financial, and legal papers, employment records, diaries, notes, newspaper articles, and printed ephemera relating to Ralph and Fanny Ellison and other family members.
  - Bell, Ida Ellison (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1912, 1921-1937, n.d.
    - Miscellany, 1918-1938, n.d.
  - Buford, Ligon
    - Citizens' Committee for Reemployment, 1938, n.d.
    - Miscellany, 1938-1945, n.d.
  - Ellison, Alfred, n.d.
  - Ellison, Fanny McConnell
    - Correspondence
      - Buford, James A., 1943-1944
      - Buford, Ligon, 1934-1945, 1963, 1980, (3 folders)
      - General, 1930-1996, n.d., (4 folders)
      - Warren, Billy ("Willy") and George, 1932-1967, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 2)
      - Warren, John, Rosanna, and Sue, 1968-1971, 1989-1992, n.d.
      - Waugh, Eliza ("Ella"), 1952-1963, n.d.
      - Waugh, Robert Harold and Mary, 1955-1957, 1967-1978, n.d.
    - Employment
      - Chicago Defender, 1939-1941, n.d., (2 folders)
      - Chicago, Ill., Board of Education, Visual Education Project
        - "Ancient Roman and Byzantine Costume," n.d., (3 folders) See also Oversize
        - Correspondence, 1938-1939, n.d. (Box 3)
        - "Costume of the Eighteenth Century," n.d., (5 folders) See also Oversize
        - Costume of the Middle Ages and seventeenth century, n.d. See also Oversize, (5 folders); (12 folders); (1 folder) (Box 4, Box 5)
        - "Egyptian Costume," n.d., (7 folders) See also Oversize
        - "Greek Costume," n.d., (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 6)
        - Miscellany, 1938-1939, n.d.
        - Persian and Chinese costume, n.d.
      - Harold L. Oram (fund-raising agency), 1950-1970, 1980-1981, n.d., (3 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1933-1955, 1967, n.d.
      - National Urban League, 1943-1946, n.d. See also Oversize
      - Negro People's Theatre, Chicago, Ill.
        - Constitution and organization, 1939, n.d.
        - Correspondence, 1937-1940, n.d., (4 folders)
        - Financial papers, 1938-1939, n.d. (Box 7)
        - Meetings, 1938-1939, n.d.
        - Membership and officers, 1938-1939, n.d.
        - Miscellany, 1936-1940, n.d., (2 folders)
        - Proposals, 1939, n.d.
      - New York City Housing Authority, New York, N.Y., 1945-1946, n.d.
      - Résumés, 1929-1956
      - United States Navy, Bureau of Yards and Docks, 1941-1942, n.d.
      - War Production Board, Traffic Section, 1937-1944
      - Works Progress Administration, 1937-1941, n.d. (Box 8)
      - World Organization of the Lamp of Brotherhood, 1956-1963, n.d.
      - Young Women's Christian Association, 1937-1941, n.d.
    - Legal papers, 1937, 1944-1954, 1963-1981, (2 folders)
    - Medical papers, 1938-1984, 1995, n.d., (4 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1929, 1937-1944, 1958-1963, n.d.
    - Notes (Box 9)
      - 1942-1995, (5 folders)
      - Undated, (5 folders); (7 folders); (1 folder) (Box 10, Box 11, Box 12)
    - School papers
      - Elementary and high school, Chicago, Ill., 1921-1932, n.d. See also Oversize
      - Fisk University, Nashville, Tenn.
        - Creative Literature, 1933
        - General, 1931-1938, n.d.
      - General, 1931, 1936-1949, n.d., (3 folders)
      - University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa
        - Contemporary British drama, 1933-1936, n.d.
        - Fundamentals of speech, 1936
        - General, 1934-1942, n.d.
        - Miscellaneous notes, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 13)
        - Modern drama, 1934-1935, n.d.
        - Stagecraft, n.d.
    - Writings, 1930-1943, n.d., (5 folders)
  - Ellison, Herbert M.
    - Correspondence, 1934-1937, n.d.
    - Miscellany, 1928-1944, n.d.
    - School papers, n.d.
  - Ellison, Ralph (Box 14)
    - Biographical material, 1943-1994, n.d., (6 folders)
    - Correspondence
      - Bell, Ida Ellison
        - 1933, (2 folders)
        - 1934-1937, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 15)
      - Bell, John, 1933-1935, n.d.
      - Brown, Lewis Thomas and Othello Albertha, 1953-1980, n.d.
      - Buford, Ligon, 1980
      - Ellison, Fanny McConnell
        - 1944-1959, (4 folders)
        - 1961-1963, 1970, 1984-1990, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - Ellison, Herbert M., 1933-1993, n.d., (6 folders)
      - Ellison, Rose Poindexter, 1939-1943, n.d.
      - Johnston, May Belle DeWitt, 1936-1953, n.d.
      - Miscellaneous family members, 1937-1983, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Diaries, 1934-1936, n.d.
    - Drawings, 1932, n.d.
    - Employment
      - Bard College, Annandale-on-Hudson, N.Y., 1956-1984, n.d., (2 folders)
      - Bennington College, Bennington, Vt., 1958, 1964, 1974, 1982-1983
      - City University of New York, New York, N.Y., 1959, 1965-1993, (2 folders)
      - General, 1937-1942
      - New York University, New York, N.Y.
        - 1960-1971, (2 folders)
        - 1972-1995, n.d., (10 folders) (Box 18)
      - Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J., 1959-1969, 1984-1992, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 19)
      - Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala., 1953-1954
      - University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill., 1959-1962, n.d.
      - Works Progress Administration, Federal Writers' Project
        - Assignments, 1938-1941, n.d.
        - Correspondence, 1938-1942, 1976-1980, n.d.
        - Miscellany, 1938-1942, n.d.
        - Reports
          - Anti-Semitism, n.d.
          - "Cultural Contributions of the American Negro," 1940, n.d.
          - "Famous Trials," 1941, (4 folders) (Box 20)
          - Folklore, ca. 1938, (2 folders)
          - History of New York, N.Y., n.d.
          - "Jews in American Theatre," ca. 1939
          - "The Negro and the War," ca. 1940, (3 folders)
          - "Negro Leadership," n.d.
          - "Negroes of New York" (Box 21)
            - Outline and comments, 1940
            - Chapt. II, n.d.
            - Chapt. V, n.d.
            - Chapt. VI, n.d.
            - Chapt. VII, n.d.
            - Chapt. XVII, n.d.
            - Chapt. XVIII, 1940
            - Notes, n.d.
          - Radio, n.d.
          - Religion and abolitionism, n.d.
          - Sociological studies, 1929, 1938, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Financial papers
      - Income and expenses
        - 1936-1937, 1945-1970, (3 folders) See also Oversize
        - 1971-1992, n.d., (5 folders) See also Oversize (Box 22)
      - Income taxes
        - 1949-1971, (4 folders)
        - 1972-1993, n.d., (8 folders) (Box 23)
      - Miscellany, 1942, 1964-1994, n.d.
      - Pensions and investments
        - 1968-1979
        - 1980-1996, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - Household papers
      - Automobile papers, 1942, 1950-1991, n.d., (3 folders)
      - Dog records, 1945-1951, 1960-1972, n.d.
      - Domestic service, 1964-1966, 1973-1976, 1995, n.d.
      - Inventories and insurance
        - 1945, 1955-1956, 1964-1973, (3 folders) See also Oversize
        - 1974-1994, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 25)
      - Key West, Fla.
        - Correspondence, 1975-1994, n.d., (3 folders)
        - Financial papers, 1976-1984 See also Oversize
        - Inventories and insurance, 1976-1977, 1990-1994, n.d.
        - Legal papers, 1976, 1986, n.d., (2 folders) See also Oversize
        - Miscellany, 1989-1994, n.d. See also Oversize (Box 26)
      - Miscellany, 1979-1980, n.d.
      - Plainfield, Mass.
        - Correspondence, 1959, 1966-1970, 1976-1986, 1995, n.d., (2 folders)
        - Financial papers, 1967-1993
        - Inventories and insurance, 1967-1968, 1993, n.d. See also Oversize
        - Legal papers, 1967
        - Miscellany, 1969, 1984-1990, n.d.
      - New York, N.Y.
        - Correspondence
          - 1940-1942, 1952, 1961-1986, (5 folders)
          - 1987-1993, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 27)
        - Financial papers, 1939-1944, 1950, 1969-1991, n.d., (2 folders)
        - Inventories, 1959, 1978-1979, n.d.
        - Legal papers, 1939, 1970-1971, 1993
        - Miscellany, 1941, 1970-1990, n.d.
        - Tenants' Association
          - 1963-1989, (4 folders)
          - 1990-1994, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Legal papers
      - Alfred Rice (law firm), 1967-1972, 1989, n.d.
      - General, 1937-1945, 1954-1959, 1964-1984, 1994
    - Medical papers, 1936-1948, 1955-1956, 1961-1994, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Military papers
      - Correspondence, 1942-1945, n.d.
      - Employment records and wages, 1942-1945, n.d.
      - Medical records, 1944-1945, n.d.
      - Miscellany, 1943-1945, n.d.
      - Publications, 1943-1944
      - Seaman's certificates and classifications, 1937-1945, n.d.
    - Newspaper and magazine articles
      - 1937, 1944-1947, (2 folders)
      - 1950-1969, (5 folders) (Box 29)
      - 1970-1994, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 30)
    - Notes
      - 1930-1943, 1951-1958, 1963-1980, 1988, (2 folders)
      - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 31)
    - Photography, 1947-1954, n.d.
    - Printed matter, 1933, 1941-1946, 1955-1994, n.d., (3 folders) See also Oversize
    - School papers (Box 32)
      - Douglass High School, Oklahoma City, Okla., 1929-1935, 1953, 1975, n.d.
      - Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala.
        - Correspondence, 1933-1936, n.d.
        - Course work, 1934-1936, n.d., (3 folders)
        - Financial papers, 1933-1936, n.d.
        - Grades and schedules, 1933-1936
        - Miscellany, 1933-1936, 1947, n.d.
        - Music, 1890, 1905-1935, n.d. See also Oversize, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 33)
        - Poetry and notes, 1934, n.d.
        - Programs, 1927-1936, 1948-1953, n.d., (2 folders)
        - Publications, 1931-1937, 1952-1953, n.d., (2 folders) See also Oversize
    - Travel (Box 34)
      - England, France, Germany, and Switzerland, 1956-1959, n.d.
      - Hong Kong, 1963
      - India, Japan, and Thailand, 1957
      - Italy, 1955-1957
      - Miscellany, 1955-1957, 1966-1967, n.d.
      - Spain, 1954
      - United States, 1953-1954, 1962-1968, 1978-1984, n.d.
  - Ellison, Lewis (Louis) Albert, 1912-1916, 1966, n.d.
  - Ellison, Rose Poindexter, 1911, 1939-1948, n.d.
  - Miscellany, 1919, 1938, 1959, n.d.
  - Warren, George, 1959-1968
  - Warren family, 1955-1968, 1975, n.d.
- General Correspondence, 1930-1996, n.d. (Box 35-79)
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence of Ralph and Fanny Ellison with friends, colleagues, and business associates.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and chronologically therein.
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, New York, N.Y., 1969-1972, 1979, 1985-1986, n.d. (Box 35)
  - Adult Education Council of Greater Chicago, Ill., 1967-1970, n.d.
  - Aldridge, John W. and Leslie, 1955-1957, n.d.
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1948-1979, n.d.
  - Allen, Betty See Container 55, Lee, Edd
  - American Heritage Publishing Co., 1959, 1972-1976
  - American Studies Association, 1965-1966
  - Amsden, Arthur and Mabel, 1947-1948, n.d.
  - Antioch College, Yellow Springs, Ohio, 1952-1954, 1968, 1979, n.d.
  - Antioch Review, 1943-1946, 1952-1954, 1964, 1976-1980, n.d. See also Container 37, Bixler, Paul
  - Arnold, Fritz and Ursula, 1950-1962, n.d.
  - Arter, Anne, Callye, and Paul, 1949-1992, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Atheneum (New York, N.Y.), 1960-1981, n.d.
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1944-1945, 1952-1953, 1960, 1966-1977, n.d.
  - "A" miscellaneous, 1939-1993, n.d., (7 folders) (Box 36)
  - Babb, Sonora, 1941-1958, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 37)
  - Ballard, Allen B., 1983
  - Barton, Robert D., 1954-1956, 1964, 1977, n.d.
  - Bearden, Romare, 1944, 1968-1971, 1986, n.d.
  - Bellow, Saul, 1952-1964, 1977, 1994, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Bibby, Henry Lambert, 1940-1944, n.d.
  - Bixler, Paul and Norma, 1958-1962, n.d. Se e also Container 35, Antioch Review
  - Blanchard, Daniel L. See Container 49, Grapevine Gallery
  - Blaustein, Albert P. and Lottie, 1956-1958, n.d.
  - Bond, Nina, 1955-1957, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Bone, Robert and Dotty, 1966-1970, 1981, n.d.
  - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1944, 1968-1970, 1986, 1993, n.d.
  - Botkin, Henry, 1964-1966, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Bourjaily, Vance and Tina, 1961-1968, 1986, n.d.
  - Branam, Virgil and Ethel, 1934, 1942-1973, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Brandel, Kuno and Elsa, 1950-1959, n.d.